Guide to the A.B. Guthrie Jr. Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, Series IV
  - Motion Pictures
    - Ben Benjamin/Famous Artists Agency, 1958-91 (Box 38, Folder 533)
    - Hecht, Hill and Lancaster Productions. Correspondence. Correspondents include: company principals James Hill, Harold Hecht, and Burt Lancaster; Fred Zinnemann (director), Irving Ravetch (screenwriter). Re: detailed negotiations and progress in writing of The Way West and The Kentuckian, and speculative projects in motion pictures and television., 1953-80 (Box 38, Folder 534)
    - Tom Gries. Correspondence. Motion picture director and writer who corresponded with A.B. Guthrie Jr. about details in filming Guthrie's Arfive and "Sun Prairie." Also discusses Gries' own The Hawaiians., 1965-70 (Box 38, Folder 535)
    - The Big Sky. Reviews, newspaper clippings, undated (Box 38, Folder 536)
    - The Way West. 1st Draft Screenplay by Irving Ravetch, Property of Burt Lancaster and Harold Hecht, mimeographed, 1954 Feb 15 (Box 38, Folder 537-538)
    - The Way West. Screenplay by Irving Ravetch, typescript original, 1954 Nov 18 (Box 38, Folder 539-540)
    - This Rebel Breed. News Release, Premiere itinerary, and newspaper clipping review, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 541)
    - "Chief Joseph Film." Correspondence. Correspondent: Porter Ward (Boise, Idaho) on story ideas, financing, 1955-67 (Box 38, Folder 542)
    - "Bent's Fort." Treatment, 1st, typescript carbon, undated (Box 38, Folder 543)
    - "Sun Prairie." From Hamlin Garland's Boy Life on the Prairie. By A.B. Guthrie Jr., teleplay, typescript carbon, undated (Box 38, Folder 544)
    - "Hadley." Half-Hour Series for Television created by Caroline Morse and A.B. Guthrie Jr., Missoula Montana, typescript carbon; also typescript original revisions with correspondence from Caroline Morse, 1970 May 28 (Box 38, Folder 545)
  - Nieman Foundation
    Guthrie was accepted as a Nieman Fellow in 1944. During his time at Harvard University, he began work on The Big Sky, published three years later.
    - Correspondence. To A.B. Guthrie Jr. from "Sunny" regarding Sunny's experience as a Nieman Fellow, 1942-43 (Box 39, Folder 546-547)
    - A.B. Guthrie Jr. Application. Written proposal, and signed letters of recommendation from Judge Max Swinford, Struthers Burt, Edward Weeks, Governor Willis, Dr. Henry H. Hill, and Dr. Charles D. Cawood, Virginius Dabney, Thomas Clark, Paul Hughes, and John F. Day., 1944 (Box 39, Folder 548)
    - Correspondence. Correspondents primarily include Louis Lyons and James B. Conant, president of Harvard University, with correspondence from A.B. Guthrie Jr. Also Nieman conference programs., 1944-90 (Box 39, Folder 549-550)
    - Coursework, 1944. Includes Harvard University catalog, class outlines, research pamphlets and guides for coursework, holograph class notes by A.B. Guthrie Jr. (Box 39, Folder 551-553)
    - Programs, publicity, memorabilia. Bread Loaf conference bulletins, programs, publicity, undated (Box 39, Folder 554)
  - Research Journals and Correspondence
    - [Oregon Trail Journal], holograph pencil, 3x6 spiral bound, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 555)
    - [Oregon Trail Journal], holograph pencil, 5x8 spiral bound, bibliographic source and expense notebook, 1948
    - [Oregon Trail Journal], Lawrence Kansas, 5x8 spiral bound, holograph ink and pencil, day journal, 1948 Jun 17
    - [Oregon Trail Journal], holograph ink and pencil, 5x8 spiral bound, 1948 Jun 23
    - "Journal of Trip Made Down the Missouri 1952," writing tablet, holograph pencil, 1952 Jun 16-25 (Box 40, Folder 556)
    - "Bud's Grizzly File," correspondence and research material, drafts of articles, 1985-86 (Box 40, Folder 557)
    - Research correspondence and inquiries to and from A.B. Guthrie Jr. on a variety of western topics; extensive holograph research notes, maps, charts, and statistical data, undated (Box 40, Folder 558)
    - Research correspondence and photocopied material, miscellaneous, undated (Box 40, Folder 559)
    - Research for Atlantic Monthly article on trapping and transporting Montana wildlife, 1945-46 (Box 40, Folder 560)
  - Studies of A.B. Guthrie Jr.
    - Wayne Chatterton, "A.B. Guthrie Jr.," Boise State University, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 40, Folder 561)
    - "Transcription of A.B. Guthrie Interview," typescript computer generated original. A.B. Guthrie Jr., Carol Guthrie, Dale Waniata, 1986 Aug
    - Sue Matthews, "Pioneer Women in the Works of Two Montana Authors: Interviews with Dorothy M. Johnson and A.B. Guthrie Jr.," Women and Western Literature, tearsheet, undated
    - Donald C. Stewart, "A.B. Guthrie's Vanishing Paradise: An Essay on Historical Fiction," Journal of the West, tearsheet: 83-95, 1976 Jul
    - "The Great West: Essay and Quotations by A.B. Guthrie Jr.," for use in Marc Gaede's book Images from the Great West. Typescript computer generated original, undated
    - Mary Scriver, "The Theology of A.B. Guthrie Jr.," typescript photocopy. Cover TLS attached. Includes additional sermons on Richard Hugo, Norman MacLean, and Robert Pirsig., 1983 (Box 40, Folder 562)
    - Barbara Meldrum, "Western American Pastoral Fiction: The Example of Guthrie," typescript photocopy, undated
    - Other Writings, undated (Box 40, Folder 563)
  - Teaching
    - Aids used for classes, workshops, and writers conferences. Includes class rolls, lecture notes, and examples of fiction in-progress., undated (Box 40, Folder 564-66)
  - Writers Conferences
    - Writers Guild of America, correspondence, 1955-64 (Box 40, Folder 567)
    - Rocky Mountain Writers Conference. Correspondence. Includes programs, 1958-59 (Box 40, Folder 568)
- Research Files: The Big Sky and The Way West, Series V
  Guthrie's organized file card system reflecting research bibliography and cross-referencing for research on The Big Sky and The Way West.
  - Card file, undated (Box 41, Folder 569)
  - Card file, undated (Box 42, Folder 570)
  - Card file, undated (Box 43, Folder 571)
  - Card file, undated (Box 44, Folder 572)
  - Card file, undated (Box 45, Folder 573)
  - Card file, undated (Box 46, Folder 574)
- Photographs, Series VI
  The Photographs series contains portraits of Guthrie at various stages of his life, including pictures of him as a child, at book signings, and with colleagues at conferences; family photographs, including pictures of his first wife Harriet Larson and other relatives; and photos of his 1950 trip down the Missouri River with Bernard DeVoto and William J. Lederer.
  - Family and colleagues, undated (Box 47, Folder 575)
  - Original and photocopies, 1901-69 (Box 47, Folder 576)
  - Originals and photocopies, 1970-90 (Box 47, Folder 577)
- Printed Material, Series VII
  This series consists of issues of publications containing articles by A. B. Guthrie Jr. A few of these periodicals also contain feature or sidebar articles on Guthrie. The magazines have been arranged alphabetically by title.
  - With contributions by Guthrie
    - ADE Bulletin No.51 "Untitled," 1-4 (Box 47, Folder 578)
    - American West 7:4 "A Matter Of Opinion Microcosm," 48, 1970 Jul
    - American West 22:4 "Seventh Cavalry, A Poem," 56, 1985 Jul-Aug
    - American West 24:3 "Westerners: A.B. Guthrie Jr. --Big Sky Author is Pulitzer Prize Winner," 70-72, 1987 Jun
    - Argosy 336:2 "The Stomper," 40, 62-65, 1953 Feb (Box 47, Folder 579)
    - Atlantic 175:4 "Sheep and Goats," 113-114, 1945 Apr
    - Atlantic 181:2 "Snakes For The Squeamish," 87-88, 1948 Feb (Box 47, Folder 580)
    - Atlantic 183:6 "This Month," 91-92, 1949 Jun
    - Atlantic 183:6 "How To Stock A Pond," 93-94, 1949 Jun
    - Boy's Life 51:9 "Young Man--Old Bear," 16-17
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 592
    - Boy's Life 55:6 "The Image," 16-17
    - Collier's, "The Fraudulent Skunk," 26-27.
    - Country Beautiful 1:2 "Who was Peter Sadler?" 10-17, 1961 Nov (Box 47, Folder 581)
    - The Delta Kappa Gamma, "What Are the Teacher's Greatest Assets?", undated
    - Esquire 28:4 "Bargain at Moon Dance," 72.
      See: Oversize, Box 54, folder 640
    - Esquire 30:5 "The Keeper of the Key," 49.
      See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 593
    - Esquire 32:5 "The Last Snake," 57.
    - Esquire 53:1 "Independence Day," 117-18.
      See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 594
    - Esquire 68:5 "Loco," 122-23
    - Family Weekly, "What Every Family Needs--A Hideaway From Life's Pressures," 6-7
    - First Bank Stock Corporation "Under The Great Bow Of Sky," 10-12, 1961
    - Ford Times 52:10 "Versailles, Kentucky," 36-39, 1960 Oct
    - Frontier 2:3 "Glen Does Some Thinking," 25-26, 1922 May
    - Frontier 3:1 "Trail Riding," poem, 13, 1922 Nov
    - Frontier 3:2 "Views" poem, 14, 1923 Mar (Box 48, Folder 582)
    - Frontier 3:3 "The Infallibility of the Infallible," 5-6, 1923 May
    - Frontier and Midland 15:3 "Indian Burial," poem, 227, 1935
    - Frontier Town [amusement park brochure] "One Man's Folly," 1-3
    - Harper's 206:1232 "Nothing Difficult About A Cow," 73-76, 1953 Jan
    - Harper's 208:1248 "Roads Running West," 68-70, 1954 May (Box 48, Folder 583)
    - Harper's 246:1474 "Reflections on a Flushed Toilet," 88, 1973 Mar
    - Holiday 9:3 "Kentucky," 34-49
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 595
    - Holiday 14:1 "U.S.A.: Adventure With History, 58-62.
    - Holiday 14:4 "Idaho," 34-36
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 596
    - Holiday 18:1 "The Rockies," 98-101
    - Holiday 24:1 "Our Lordly Mountains," 55, 102-104.
    - Holiday 34:2 "The Great Rockies," 28-41.
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 597
    - Holiday 35:5 "The Animal Actors of Eighteenth Street," 88.
    - Holiday 37:3 "An April in Montana," 70-72.
    - Liberty, "Old Mother Hubbard," 34, 1946 May 11
    - Life 46:15 "How the West Was Won, Part 2," 79-98.
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 598
    - Montana Farmer's Union News (newspaper), "Sirs, We Are Americans!" 4, 1958 Feb 26
    - Montana Magazine 2:2 "Four Prestigous Montana Writers: Their Works and Thoughts on Montana," 26-49, 1980 Nov-Dec
    - Montana Magazine 4:4 "The Historical Novel," 1-8, 1954
    - Montana Magazine 12:4 "Swing Low, Sweet Chariot," 28-30, 1982 Mar-Apr
    - Montana Magazine No.82 "Two Authors: A.B. Guthrie: Thinking About Montana and James Welch: A New Novel, An Old Wound," 50-60, 1987 Mar-Apr (Box 48, Folder 584)
    - Montana Magazine No.85 "The Rocky Mountain Front," 26-30, 1987 Sep-Oct
    - Montana Magazine: The Big Sky Country 1:1 "Treasure State: Land of the High Sky," 2-5, 1964
    - Montana Magazine of History 4:4 "The Historical Novel: Tramp or Teacher?", 1-8, 1954
    - Montana Outdoors 5:3 "Message to DeVoto," 43, 1974 May-Jun (Box 48, Folder 585)
    - Montana Parade, Great Falls Tribune, Saturday Review 33:25 "Virtue Plundered in Kentucky," 11-12; ABG's review of Robert Penn Warren's World Enough and Time, 1950 Jun 24
    - Montana Parade [special "Pictures and State Features" pull-out section] re: Filming of The Big Sky and Shane, 1951 Aug 19
    - Mother Earth News American Country 2:2 "Trout...Unlimited? on Western Waters," by A.B. Guthrie, 18-21, 1988
    - Mother Earth News 118 "Landscapes: My West," 48-55, 1989 Jul-Aug
    - Nature Conservancy News 29:1 "The Big Swamp, Many Persons Butte," 16-18., 1979 Jan-Feb
    - New York Times Book Review 7:1, "Fiction--With a Hold on History."
    - New York Times Magazine, "A Town Divided by the Grizzly," 22, 1986 Aug 31
    - New York Times Magazine 6:18 "How to Live at Fifty-eight Below."
    - Nieman Reports 12:1 "DeVoto - A Memoir," 3-6, 1958 Jan
    - Nieman Reports 12:2 "Guthrie Blasts Charges By Legion's Committee," 18, 1958 Apr
    - Omnibook 9:11 The Big Sky [abridgment], 79-120, 1947 Oct (Box 48, Folder 586)
    - Omnibook No.5 The Big Sky [abridgment], 1-44, 1948 Jun
    - Parade, "Requiem for Old Ephraim," 18-21., 1983 Jul 24
    - Prime Time 1:8 "Reflections: On Marrying A Younger Woman," 96-98., 1980 Aug
    - Read 7:12 "Captured by Indians," 16-20, "What the West Means to Me," 21, 1958 Mar 1
    - Saturday Evening Post, "Posse on the Marsh," 106 (tearsheet), undated
    - Saturday Review 33:25 "World Enough and Time," review by ABG, 11, 1950 Jun 24 (Box 48, Folder 587)
    - Saturday Review 41:45 "A Mighty March of Tireless Men," 19-20; ABG's review of David Lavender's Land of Giants: the Drive to the Pacific Northwest, 1750-1950, 1958 Nov 8
    - Saturday Review 43:8 Book review of The Big It by William Eastlake, and response from ABG, "High Noon for Courage," 19, 1960 Feb 20
    - Saturday Evening Post 220:7 "Mountain Medicine," 27-28
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 599
    - Saturday Evening Post 225:21 "The Badlands Are Still Bad," 34-36
    - Sierra Club Bulletin 52:4 "The Little Blackout," 5-6, 1967 Apr-May
    - Southwest Review 36:2 "Ebbie," 85-89, 1951
    - Travel & Leisure 4:4 "The Big Sky Revisited," 24-7, 1974 Apr
    - Vogue, 3:1 "Remember the Parsley," 5, 1948
    - Western American Literature 7:3 "Why Write About the West?" 163-169, undated
    - Westways 70:3 "Horse, Boss and Chuggy," 29-31, 1978 Mar (Box 49, Folder 588)
    - Westways 70:12 "Out In The Cold," 21-23, 1978 Dec
    - Westways 72:1 "Don't Rush the Gravy," 38-40, 1980 Jan
    - Westways 79:7 "Big Sky Writer," 38, 1987 Jul
    - Winner's Circle 2, by George E. Mason and William D. Sheldon. Boston; Allyn and Bacon. Second Edition, "Forest Fire," 84-89, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 589)
    - Works in Progress No.2 "Arfive," 34-56, undated
    - The Writer 62:11 "Characters and Compassion," 359-362, 1949 Nov
  - Works by others
    - Richard Astro, "The Big Sky and the Limits of Wilderness Fiction," W estern American Literature 9:2 105-114, 1974 Aug (Box 49, Folder 590)
    - Carl Carmer, Review of "These Thousand Hills--Book of the Week," Saturday Review 39:46 17, 1956 Nov 17
    - Robert Littell, "A Speakeasy Club for Your Town," Future 2:11 32-34, 1940 Jul
    - Elsie M. McDowall, "My Life Lies Grand Among the Hills," Frontier 5:3 4-5, 1925 May
    - Allan Nevins, Review of The Big Sky, "Wild Mountain Melody," Saturday Review 13:18 9-10, 1947 May 3
  - Miscellaneous printed material, undated (Box 49, Folder 591)
- Audio and Video Recordings, Series VIII
  These recordings document Guthrie's speaking style from the late 1940s until 1990 and include tapes of radio broadcasts, interviews, readings, and speeches. In addition, there are 15 discs of the testimonial dinner held for Guthrie at the University of Kentucky after he won the Pulitzer Prize; they feature tributes to Guthrie by friends, students and colleagues, many of whom are also represented in the correspondence. These materials are housed in the Historical Sound Recordings Department of Sterling Memorial Library.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiodiscs (description only here)
    15 12-inch metal based Audiodisc Custom Recordings, numbered sides 1-30. Testimonial dinner for A.B. Guthrie Jr., 19 May 1950, at the University of Kentucky. Dan Bowmar, master of ceremonies, long-time co-worker at the Lexington Leader and friend of ABG; Harmon Lee Donovan, president of the University of Kentucky; Dr. Theodore Morrison, Harvard University, ABG's mentor while writing The Big Sky; William J. Lederer, novelist who journeyed the length of the Missouri River with ABG; English 117 skit satarizing Guthrie's character from The Big Sky and The Way West and written and acted by ABG's students; Clay Stuart, of the Speakeasy Club founded by ABG; and A.B. Guthrie Jr. See also 1 C-60 audio cassette recordings of same entitled "A.B. Guthrie Recordings 1, 2 and 3."
    1 12-inch metal based Audiodisc Custom Recording, "Jay Jay--A.B. Guthrie Show, Side #1 & 2." ca. May 1953. A biographical tribute broadcast on Lexington, Kentucky's WBLK readio on Guthrie's departure from Kentucky to Montana. See also 1 C-60 audio cassette recording of same entitled "A.B. Guthrie Recordings, 3."
    1 12-inch metal based Audiodisc Custom Recording, "For ABG, Jr.--start inside, 7 May 1953." Radio broadcast on WBLK, Lexington, Kentucky. ABG is interviewed about motion pictures The Big Sky and Shane. Also discusses literary adaptations to film, impending departure for Hollywood to write a screenplay from Felix Holt's Gabriel Horn, released as The Kentuckian (1955). Also discusses teaching of writing to students, getting stories published, challenges in working with a literary agent.
    1 7-inch Federal Perma Disc customized recording. "Bud on Snakes." One side only, n.d. Speech given at the Speakeasy Club, Lexington, Kentucky.
    - "A.B. Guthrie Recordings 1," made from audiodiscs. Includes: a) radio interview broadcast on WBLK, Lexington, Kentucky, 7 May 1953; b) four of the speeches given at a testimonial dinner for A.B. Guthrie Jr., 19 May 1950, at the University of Kentucky. Speakers include Dan Bowmar, Harmon Lee Donovan, Theodore Morrison, and William J. Lederer (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889655)
    - "A.B. Guthrie Recordings 2," made from audiodiscs. Includes remainder of testimonial dinner speeches: a) William J. Lederer (concluded); b) English 117 skit satarizing Guthrie's character from The Big Sky and The Way West and written and acted by ABG's students; c) Arthur Lloyd; d) Ed Templin; e) Clay Stuart, of the Speakeasy Club (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889663)
    - "A.B. Guthrie Recordings 3," made from audiodiscs. Includes: a) A.B. Guthrie Jr. speech from testimonial dinner; b) "Jay Jay--A.B. Guthrie Show, Side #1 & 2." ca. May 1953 (a biographical tribute broadcast on Lexington, Kentucky's WBLK radio on Guthrie's departure from Kentucky to Montana); c) "Bud on Snakes," speech given at the Speakeasy Club, Lexington, Kentucky (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889671)
    - "The Arizona Daily Star Third Annual Book Author Luncheon", interview with A.B. Guthrie Jr., Durhm[?], Auel, Spence (audiocassette), 1983 December 3; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889689)
    - "M.E.N. Spot--Big Sky, Fair Land" (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889697)
    - "Montana Minutes: Historical Vignettes for Radio Celebrating Montana's Centennial," A. B. Guthrie Jr - Lynne F. Turner (audiocassette), 1989 August 6; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889705)
    - "Montana Writers Conference," (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889713)
      The contents are listed on the audiocassette.
      1. Opening Remarks
      2. Two Poems: "Ear Mountain" and "Montana"
      3. Digressions
      4. The Front to Me
      5. Fishing Journal
      6. "Mixed Chorus"
      7. My Thanks
      8. "For a Little While, Goodbye"
    - "Montana Writers Conference" (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889721)
    - A. B. Guthrie Jr. reading "Mowgli's Brothers," recorded for Kelley and Tommy Guthrie (audiocassette), early 1970s; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889739)
    - Once Upon A Pond, readings by A.B. Guthrie Jr. (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889747)
      Readings include "Hello There", "The Flood Like None Before", and "G. H. Owl".
    - "Talks on Writing by A. B. Guthrie Jr." (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1984 January 13; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889754)
    - "Talks on Writing by A. B. Guthrie Jr." (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1984 January 14; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889762)
    - "Tribute to A.B. Guthrie Jr., by Charles E. Hood," Friends of the Library Banquet, University of Montana (audiocassette), 1981 April 14; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889770)
    - "Unrehearsed interview with A. B. Guthrie Jr. for the University of Kentucky Oral History Program", conducted by Bill Cooper at "The Barn" near Choteau, Montana (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1979 June 16; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889788)
    - "Unrehearsed interview with A. B. Guthrie Jr. for the University of Kentucky Oral History Program", conducted by Bill Cooper at "The Barn" near Choteau, Montana (2 of 3 audiocassettes), 1979 June 16; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889796)
    - "Unrehearsed interview with A. B. Guthrie Jr. for the University of Kentucky Oral History Program", conducted by Bill Cooper at "The Barn" near Choteau, Montana (3 of 3 audiocassettes), 1979 June 16; 1 (Box 55, Item barcode 39002104889804)
    - "A Path to America's Wilderness," Bob Marshall Foundation, Cameo appearance by A.B. Guthrie Jr., 1986; 1 (Box 56, Item barcode 39002104889648)
      Note on the videocassette reads: Bud's part in this is small, but you might want it. This way never shown to my knowledge as it didn't turn out too well.
- Oversize
  - Printed Material with contributions by Guthrie
    - Boy's Life 51:9 "Young Man - Old Bear," 16-17, 1961 Sep (Box 50, Folder 592)
    - Boy's Life 55:6 "The Image," 16-17, 1965 Jun
    - Collier's, "The Fraudulent Skunk," 26-27, 1951 Apr 28
    - Esquire 30:5 "The Keeper of the Key," 49, 1948 Nov (Box 50, Folder 593)
    - Esquire 32:5 "The Last Snake," 57, 1949 Nov
    - Esquire 28:4 "Bargain at Moon Dance," 72, 1952 Oct
    - Esquire 53:1 "Independence Day," 117-118, 1960 Jan (Box 50, Folder 594)
    - Esquire 58:5 "Loco," 122-23, 1967 Nov
    - Family Weekly, "What Every Family Needs - A Hideaway From Life's Pressures," 6-7, 1969 Jan 26
    - Holiday 9:3 "Kentucky," 34-49, 1951 Mar (Box 51, Folder 595)
    - Holiday 14:1 "U.S.A.: Adventure with History," 58-62, 1953 Jul
    - Holiday 14:4 "Idaho," 34-36, 1954 Jun (Box 51, Folder 596)
    - Holiday 18:1 "The Rockies," 98-101, 1955 Jul
    - Holiday 24:1 "Our Lordly Mountains," 55, 102-104, 1958 Jul
    - Holiday 34:2 "The Great Rockies," 28-49, 1963 Aug (Box 51, Folder 597)
    - Holiday 35:5 "The Animal Actors of Eighteenth Street," 88, 1964 May
    - Holiday 37:3 "An April in Montana," 70-72, 1965 Mar
    - Life 46:15 "How the West was Won, Part 2," 79-88, 1959 Apr 13 (Box 51, Folder 598)
    - New York Times Book Review 7:1, "Fiction--With A Hold on History", 1950 Dec 3
    - New York Times Magazine, Section 6:18, "How to Live at Fifty-eight Below", 1954 Jul 31
    - Saturday Evening Post 220:7 "Mountain Medicine," 27-28, 1947 Aug 16 (Box 51, Folder 599)
    - Saturday Evening Post 225:21 "The Badlands are Still Bad," 34-36, 1952 Nov 22
- A. B. Guthrie Jr. Papers Addition, Series IX
  The A. B. Guthrie Jr. Papers Addition consists of three boxes of material acquired from Mrs. A. B. Guthrie Jr. in 1993. The papers include four folders of correspondence, with additional reviews, subject files, and printed material. The material was arranged in a similar order of the A. B. Guthrie Jr. Papers in series above.
  - Correspondence
    - Family, chronological, 1973, undated (Box 52, Folder 600)
    - Named files: Walter T. Edmonds, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 601)
    - Chronological, 1950-63 (Box 52, Folder 602)
    - Publishers: Houghton Mifflin, 1980, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 603)
  - Writings
    - Books
      - The Big Sky (1947): Reviews, undated (Box 52, Folder 604)
      - The Way West (1949): Reviews, undated (Box 52, Folder 605)
      - The Last Valley (1975)
        - Research material, 1973-75 (Box 52, Folder 606)
        - Reviews, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 607)
      - The Genuine Article (1977): Reviews, undated (Box 52, Folder 608)
      - No Second Wind (1980)
        - "Editorial suggestions from Ruth Hapgood", undated (Box 52, Folder 609)
        - Reviews, 1980, undated (Box 52, Folder 610)
      - Fair Land, Fair Land (1982): Reviews (Box 52, Folder 611)
    - Articles
      - "Adventure with History-- Holiday Magazine, July 1953," typescript carbon, 1953 Jul (Box 52, Folder 612)
      - "Our Lordly Mountains-- Holiday, July 1958," typescript carbon, 1957-58 (Box 52, Folder 613)